Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. New business records, 1924-2007 and undated, bulk 1980-1989 RL.00731
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Chicago Office Additions, 1973-2007 and undated; 1
  - New Business Prospects, 1973-2007 and undated; 2
    - Mattel--Barbie 40th anniversary (Caras de Puerto Rico; in Spanish), 1999 (Box CH34)
    - Mattel--Correspondence, 1993-1994 (Box CH68)
    - Mattel--Presentations, undated; 2 folders (Box CH34)
    - Maytag--Corporation overview, 2000 (Box CH34)
    - McDonald's--Correspondence, 2001 (Box CH35)
    - McDonnell Douglas, 1993-2001 (Box CH35)
    - McDonnell Douglas--Account overview, 1995 (Box CH35)
    - McDonnell Douglas--Historical print advertising, undated (Box CH35)
    - McDonnell Douglas--Presentation, 1994-1995; 2 folders (Box CH35)
    - Mead Johnson Worldwide--International product grid, 1995 (Box CH35)
    - Mead Johnson Worldwide--Project Edison, undated (Box CH35)
    - Mead Office Supplies, 1999 (Box CH35)
    - Merrill Lynch--Presentation, 1998 (Box CH35)
    - Metra--Project Ride, 1998 (Box CH35)
    - Michael's Crafts, 1996 (Box CH35)
    - Microsoft, 1994 (Box CH35)
    - Microsoft/Lyons, 1996 (Box CH36)
    - Midas International, 1979-1995; 3 folders (Box CH36)
    - Midas International--Communications plan, 1978 (Box CH36)
    - Midas International--First presentation, undated (Box CH69)
    - Midas International--Company overview, 1978 (Box CH36)
    - Midas International--Presentations, 1995 and undated; 4 folders (Box CH36)
    - Midwest Bell, 1983; 2 folders (Box CH37)
    - Midwest Bell--Case histories, 1983 (Box CH37)
    - Midwest Bell--Fact book #1, 1983; 3 folders (Box CH37)
    - Midwest Bell--Fact book #2, 1983; 2 folders (Box CH38)
    - Midwest Bell--New nation of communications, undated (Box CH38)
    - Midwest Bell--Presentation, 1983 (Box CH38)
    - Midwest Bell--Seminar, 1982 (Box CH38)
    - Miller Brewing, 1995-1999 (Box CH38)
    - Miller Brewing--Discussion guide, 1999 (Box CH38)
    - Miller Brewing--Lite Ice, 1994 (Box CH38)
    - Miller Brewing--Lite Ice, 1994; 2 folders (Box CH39)
    - Miller Brewing--Media consolidation, 1994; 2 folders (Box CH39)
    - Miller Brewing--Presentation, 1994 (Box CH38)
    - Milton Bradley--Directory of corporate affiliations, 1997 (Box CH39)
    - Molson Beer, 1996 (Box CH39)
    - Monsanto, 1994 (Box CH39)
    - Montgomery Ward, 1990-1995; 2 folders (Box CH39)
    - Motorola, 1992-1997; 4 folders (Box CH39)
    - Motorola--Brand strategy assignment, 1995 (Box CH40)
    - Motorola--Building global leadership in a dynamic market, 1992 (Box CH40)
    - Motorola--Integrated radio system ad agency review, 1994 (Box CH40)
    - Motorola--Olympics, 1996-1997; 2 folders (Box CH40)
    - Motorola--Pitch/Questionnaire, 1992 (Box CH40)
    - Motorola--Presentations, 1995-1996; 2 folders (Box CH40)
    - Nabisco, 1984-1985 (Box CH40)
    - Nabisco, 1984-1999; 3 folders (Box CH41)
    - Nabisco--Background, 1983-1984; 2 folders (Box CH41)
    - Nabisco--Clippings, 1983-1984; 2 folders (Box CH41)
    - Nabisco--Creative presentation, 1985 (Box CH41)
    - Nabisco--Invoices, 1984-1985 (Box CH41)
    - Nabisco--Meeting, 1985 (Box CH42)
    - Nabisco--Project Polly, 1984-1985 (Box CH42)
    - Nabisco--Wheat Thins/Better Cheddar, 1985; 2 folders (Box CH42)
    - National Honey Board, 1991 (Box CH42)
    - National Pork Producers Council, 1994; 3 folders (Box CH42)
    - National Ski Areas Association, 1998 (Box CH42)
    - NEC, 1992-1994 (Box CH42)
    - New England Consulting Group, 1997 (Box CH43)
    - Nestle, 2003 (Box CH43)
    - Nike, 1993-1994 (Box CH43)
    - Nintendo, 1990-1995; 2 folders (Box CH43)
    - Nintendo--Branding strategy (U.K.), 1994 (Box CH43)
    - Nordic Track, 1994-1995 (Box CH43)
    - Northern Telecom (NorTel)--Creative, 1992 (Box CH69)
    - Northern Telecom (NorTel)--Presentations, 1994-1996; 3 folders (Box CH43)
    - Northern Trust, 1978 (Box CH44)
    - Northwestern Memorial Hospital, 1997-2001 and undated; 3 folders (Box CH44)
    - NutraSweet, 1995-1996 (Box CH44)
    - NutraSweet--Presentation, 1990 (Box CH44)
    - Office Depot, 1996 (Box CH44)
    - Office Depot--Presentations, 1996 (Box CH44)
    - Oprah Winfrey Show, 1995 (Box CH44)
    - Oshkosh B' Gosh, 1995-1997; 2 folders (Box CH44)
    - Oshkosh B 'Gosh--Kid's Initiative, 1998 (Box CH44)
    - Outboard Marine--Presentations, 1995; 2 folders (Box CH44)
    - Pabst Brewing, 1977 (Box CH44)
    - Pearle Vision, 2003 (Box CH45)
    - Pet Inc. (Old El Paso), 1981 (Box CH45)
    - PetSmart, 1996-1997; 3 folders (Box CH45)
    - Pillsbury (Grand Metropolitan Food Service), 1994; 3 folders (Box CH45)
    - Pillsbury (Grand Metropolitan Food Service), 1997-1998; 2 folders (Box CH46)
    - Pizza Hut--Operation Big Foot, 1993 (Box CH46)
    - Pizza Hut--Project Mystic, 1999 (Box CH46)
    - Popeye's Chicken, 1995 (Box CH46)
    - Princess Cruises, 1995; 2 folders (Box CH46)
    - Princess Cruises--Brand positioning, 1995 (Box CH46)
    - Princess Cruises--Love Boat, 1995 (Box CH46)
    - Promus Hotel Corporation, 1998 (Box CH46)
    - Pure Fishing, 2000 (Box CH46)
    - Quality Chekd Dairy Products Association, 1983 (Box CH47)
    - Quaker Oat, 1994-1995 (Box CH47)
    - Radio Flyer, 1994 (Box CH47)
    - Radisson, 1992-1994; 3 folders (Box CH47)
    - Raytheon, 1994 (Box CH47)
    - Reader's Digest, 1995-1996 (Box CH47)
    - Reality Pacific--Project China Bridge, 1995 (Box CH48)
    - Re/Max, 1993-1998; 3 folders (Box CH48)
    - Ritz Carlton, 1991-1994 (Box CH48)
    - Royal Appliance (Dirt Devil), 1992-1995; 2 folders (Box CH48)
    - Royal Appliance (Eureka), 1992-1995 (Box CH48)
    - Rubbermaid, 1997 (Box CH48)
    - Rubbermaid, 1997 (Box CH49)
    - Rubbermaid--Little Tikes (Children's furniture etc.), 1997 (Box CH49)
    - Saban Children's Entertainment--Mighty Morphin Power Rangers, 1994 (Box CH49)
    - Saban Children's Entertainment--Chuck-E-Cheese, 1994 (Box CH49)
    - Saban Children's Entertainment--JWT Entertainment Services, 1994 (Box CH49)
    - Saban Children's Entertainment--Konami, 1994 (Box CH49)
    - Saban Children's Entertainment--The Window (Off the Street Club), 1994 (Box CH49)
    - Safeway Stores, undated (Box CH49)
    - Salton, 2001 (Box CH49)
    - Sanwa Business Credit, 1998 (Box CH49)
    - S.C. Johnson, 1975-1978 (Box CH49)
    - S.C. Johnson, 1993-1995; 2 folders (Box CH50)
    - S.C. Johnson--Presentations, 1973-1974; 2 folders (Box CH50)
    - S.C. Johnson--Staffing proposal, 1979 (Box CH50)
    - Schering-Plough, 1999 (Box CH50)
    - Schick Wilkinson Sword, 1996; 2 folders (Box CH50)
    - Schooners Bay International, 1994 (Box CH50)
    - Scott Paper, 1994 (Box CH50)
    - Seagram, 1993-1994 (Box CH51)
    - Searle, G.D., 1981 (Box CH51)
    - Searle (Ambien), 1993 (Box CH51)
    - Sears, 1992-1996 (Box CH51)
    - Sears--Banking industry study, 1984 (Box CH51)
    - Sears--Case studies, undated (Box CH51)
    - Sears--Case studies--Bank Americard/Visa, 1984 (Box CH51)
    - Sears--Case studies--MasterCard, 1984 (Box CH51)
    - Sears--Case studies--Visa International, 1983 (Box CH51)
    - Sears--Competitive card analysis, 1984 (Box CH51)
    - Sears--Creating a climate for deregulation of financial services, 1984 (Box CH51)
    - Sears--Discover card external correspondence, 1984 (Box CH51)
    - Sears--Discover card launch, 1984 (Box CH51)
    - Sears--Discover card video scripts, undated (Box CH51)
    - Sears--New York Office credit card presentation, undated (Box CH51)
    - Sears--Presentations, 1984; 4 folders (Box CH52)
    - Sears--Presentation photos, undated (Box CH52)
    - Sears--Project Ace, 1984; 4 folders (Box CH52)
    - Sears--Project Ace, 1984 (Box CH53)
    - Sears--Sears card strategy, undated (Box CH53)
    - Sears--Service establishment studies, 1984 (Box CH53)
    - Select Resources International, 1996 (Box CH53)
    - Serta, 1992 (Box CH53)
    - Seven-Up (7-Up)--Mailing, 1993 (Box CH53)
    - Sherwin Williams, 1983, 1995; 4 folders (Box CH53)
    - Sherwin Williams--Meeting, 1983 (Box CH53)
    - Sherwin Williams--Presentation "J. Walter Paints", 1983 (Box CH53)
    - Sherwin Williams--T-Plan, 1983 (Box CH53)
    - Shopko, 1992 (Box CH54)
    - Shop Talk, 2000 (Box CH54)
    - Sony, 1998; 2 folders (Box CH54)
    - Sony--CAVG (Consumer Audio Video Group), 1998; 3 folders (Box CH54)
    - Sony--Presentations, 1998; 3 folders (Box CH54)
    - Southland (7-11), 1980-1981 (Box CH55)
    - Southland (7-11)--Advertising research, undated (Box CH55)
    - Southland (7-11)--Brand personality, 1980 (Box CH55)
    - Southland (7-11)--Consumer perceptions, 1980 (Box CH55)
    - Southland (7-11)--Meeting, 1980 (Box CH55)
    - Southland (7-11)--National penetration study, 1981 (Box CH55)
    - Southland (7-11)--Opportunity segments, 1981 (Box CH55)
    - Southland (7-11)--Social research, 1981 (Box CH55)
    - Spencer Stuart Online, 2000; 2 folders (Box CH55)
    - Spiegel, 1990-1993 (Box CH55)
    - Sprint, 1996 (Box CH56)
    - Sprint, 1996 (Box CH68)
    - Steak & Ale Restaurants, 1981; 2 folders (Box CH56)
    - Steel Recycling Institute, 1996 (Box CH56)
    - Stokley Van Camp, 1982-1983; 4 folders (Box CH56)
    - Stouffer's, 2004; 2 folders (Box CH57)
    - Stouffer's--Lean Cuisine, 1991-1992 (Box CH57)
    - Stouffer's Hotel Group, 1993 (Box CH57)
    - Sunbeam-Oster, 1994-1998; 3 folders (Box CH57)
    - Sunbeam-Oster, 1994-1996; 3 folders (Box CH58)
    - Tambrands, 1992-1996 (Box CH58)
    - Telular, 1994 (Box CH58)
    - Tenneco Packaging, 1996 (Box CH58)
    - Tenneco Packaging--Hefty, 1999-2000 (Box CH58)
    - TGI Friday's, 1994; 6 folders (Box CH59)
    - TGI Friday's, 1999-2000; 5 f (Box CH60)
    - Toshiba, 1999 (Box CH60)
    - Toys R Us, 1996 (Box CH61)
    - Tribune Interactive, 1999 (Box CH61)
    - True Value, 1998; 2 folders (Box CH61)
    - True Value--"Project Thumb", 1998; 2 folders (Box CH61)
    - U-Access, 2000 (Box CH61)
    - United Airlines, 1994 (Box CH61)
    - United Airlines, 1996-1998; 4 folders (Box CH62)
    - United States Marine Corps--Presentation, undated (Box CH62)
    - United States Military--Project JRAP (Joint Recruiting Advertising Program), 1996 (Box CH62)
    - United States Steel (Marathon), 1983 (Box CH62)
    - Universal Studios, 1996 (Box CH62)
    - University of Illinois Medical Center--Request for proposal form, 2007 (Box CH62)
    - U.S. Shoe, 1993 (Box CH62)
    - Utilicorp United, 1994 (Box CH62)
    - Utilicorp United, 1994; 2 folders (Box CH63)
    - Vaughan Brothers Coffee, 1993 (Box CH63)
    - Video Software Dealers Association (VSDA), 1999-2000; 2 folders (Box CH63)
    - Volume Shoe (Payless), 1980-1986; 3 folders (Box CH63)
    - Volume Shoe (Payless), 1980-1986; 3 folders (Box CH64)
    - Volume Shoe (Payless)--Awareness & attitude survey, 1981 (Box CH64)
    - Volume Shoe (Payless)--Industry overview, 1980 (Box CH64)
    - Volume Shoe (Payless)--Recommendations, 1981 (Box CH64)
    - Vview.com, 1999 (Box CH64)
    - Walgreens, 2001 (Box CH64)
    - Warner Vison Entertainment--Kids questionnaire, 1995 (Box CH64)
    - Wesley-Jessen, 1992-1994 (Box CH64)
    - Western Publishing Company, 1991 (Box CH65)
    - Western Publishing/Gold Books, 1993-1995; 3 folders (Box CH65)
    - Western Union, 2001-2002; 4 folders (Box CH65)
    - Western Union, 2002; 4 folders (Box CH66)
    - Whirlpool, 1995-2001; 3 folders (Box CH66)
    - Whirlpool/Kitchen Aid, 1996-1997 (Box CH66)
    - White Westinghouse/Frigidaire, 1994; 2 folders (Box CH67)
    - Whitman-Hart, 1999 (Box CH67)
    - Wilson Sporting Goods, 1991-1996; 2 folders (Box CH67)
    - Wine.com, 2000 (Box CH67)
    - WLS-TV--Creative recommendations, 1982 (Box CH67)
    - WLS-TV--Presentation, 1982 (Box CH67)
    - WLS-TV--Recommendations, 1982 (Box CH67)
    - Zenith Data Systems, 1995 (Box CH67)
- Oversize Materials, 1924-1994 and undated, 7 boxes
  Comprised of large format materials removed from elsewhere in the collection. Includes case histories, clippings, presentation books, storyboards, spreads, and market research. Arranged alphabetically.
  - General
    - unspecified (Box OV1)
    - An Intimate Picture of the World's Largest Advertising Agency, 1935 (Box OV1)
    - J. Walter Thompson Company: An Analysis, 1938
      - Forward--History (Box OV1)
      - Creative Accomplishments (Box OV1)
      - Records (Box OV1)
    - J. Walter Thompson Portfolio Comprising of Facts and Figures, circa 1924 (Box OV1)
    - Successful Examples of Mass Education by Clients of J. Walter Thompson Company, circa 1965 (Box OV1)
  - Atlanta Office
    - New Business presentation materials, circa 1984 (Box OV2)
  - Companies
    - A&P Clean Copies, 1990 Jan. 9 (Box OV3)
    - Alpha Beta presentation book, 1986, 6 folders (Box OV3)
    - Circuit City clippings, 1989 (Box OV4)
    - Ford Motor Company leave-behind books (JWT-Australia), circa 1989, 3 books (Box OV4)
      [Includes Our Views and Strategies, Our Credentials, Why J. Walter Thompson]
    - Goodyear Tire and Rubber Company storyboards, undated, 2 folders (Box OV5)
    - Kraft--NatuBlend spreads, undated (Box OV5)
    - Löwenbräu market research, 1985 (Box OV5)
    - North American Philips Corporation--Norelco sketches, circa 1986-1987 (Box OV6)
    - Pan Am briefing, 1988 (Box OV6)
    - Sun Microsystems, Two of the World's Cooler Networks, circa 1994 (Box OV6)
    - Zale Corporation, DeBeers proof, 1986 (Box OV6)
    - Von's and the More Agency, 1987, 7 folders (Box OV7)
  - Scrapbooks
    - Sam Meek's Blue Book, circa 1927 (Box OV8)
- Audiovisual Materials, 1982-2006, undated, 1 box
  Includes audiocassettes, CD's, DVD's, VHS tapes, and U-matic videotapes.
  Conditions Governing Access note
  Restrictions on Access: Original audiovisual materials are closed to researchers until Use Copies can be produced. Please contact Research Services for more information.]
  - Bertolli Extra Light, :60 radio spot. Format: 1/4" audiotape reel. TRT: 1:00. (Box AV1)
  - Brian Johnson; Effective, Distinctive Advertising Prepared for Nintendo, 1994 Apr. 12. Format: U-matic videotape. TRT: 10:00. (Box AV1)
  - Brian's Video for Nintendo,1994 Apr. 14. Format: U-matic videotape. TRT: 20:00. (Box AV1)
  - Burger King-JWT repitch, undated,. Format: VHS. TRT: Unknown. (Box AV1)
  - Fla. Citrus agency briefing, 1983 June 8. Format: Audiocassette. TRT: Unknown (C-90). (Box AV1)
  - Glidden Company--JWT audio-visual center, undated. Format: U-matic videotape. TRT: 10:00. (Box AV1)
  - Hallmark Cards, circa 1986 Apr. 21. Format: Audiocassette. TRT: Unknown (C-90). (Box AV1)
  - IBM Pro Printers--3 :60 radio spots. Format: Audiocassette. TRT: 1:30. (Box AV1)
  - JWT Award-winning food advertisements reel, 2005 Nov. 3. Format: DVD (.mov file format). TRT: 28:00. (Box AV1)
    [Includes commercials for Got Milk, John West Salmon, Kellogg's, Kit-Kat, Meijer, Nong UHT, Special K, Tabasco, and Nestlé Yorkie campaigns.]
  - JWT-Chicago, Creating Popular Campaigns for Real People, 2006 Nov. 29. Format: DVD. TRT: 3:21. (Box AV1)
  - JWT-Chicago--Hyatt questionnaire--Express Checkout, 1992 Nov. 24. Format: U-matic videotape. TRT: 30:00. (Box AV1)
  - JWT-Glidden testimonials, undated,. Format: VHS. TRT: 5:00. (Box AV1)
  - JWT history, 2006 May 3,. Format: DVD. TRT: 60:00. (Box AV1)
    [Includes history of JWT, history of print, history of broadcast, and history of international.]
  - JWT Microsoft pitch, 1994 Apr. 6. Format: U-matic videotape. TRT: 8:53. (Box AV1)
    [Includes commercials for e.p.t, Sprint, Jaguar, Bell Atlantic, Prodigy, Esso, 7-Eleven, Calif. Tourism, Ford, Calif. Lottery, Nintendo, and Kodak campaigns.]
  - Nintendo video mailer, 1994 Apr. 19 (Howard Lincoln and Brian Johnson). Format: VHS. TRT: 5:00. (Box AV1)
  - Sprint historical review, JWT-San Francisco office, 1982-1993,. Format: VHS. TRT: 60:00. (Box AV1)
  - UDIA--Milk pitch,1993 Oct. 25. Format: U-matic videotape. TRT: 30:00. (Box AV1)
  - U.S. Navy--Roger Enrico interview, 1987 June 4. Format: Audiocassette. TRT: Unknown (C-90). (Box AV1)
- Restricted Materials, 1986-2006, 2 boxes
  Restrictions on Access: Materials are closed to non-JWT researchers for 15 years from the date of creation.
  - General (Box R1)
    - Chicago Office planning toolkit, 2006 (Box R1)
    - Presentation: The Future: How Do We Get It?, 2000 (Box R1)
    - Presentation: Who We Are, circa 2000 (Box R1)
    - Retail New Business Conference, 2005, 2 folders (Box R1)
  - Companies
    - L.L. Bean, Connecting People Outdoors Since 1912, 2005 (Box R1)
    - Nextel, credentials presentation, 2003 (Box R1)
    - Novell, advertising strategy recommendations, 2002 (Box R1)
    - Smirnoff (Diageo), Project 21, circa 2005 (Box R1)
  - Restricted Personnel Records, 1986-1987
    Restrictions on Access: These materials contain sensitive employment or personnel related materials and are closed to non-JWT researchers for 40 years from the date of termination of employment or 25 years from the date of death of employees.
    - California State Lottery, professional skills inventories, 1986 (Box R2)
    - Lipton, one-on-one releases, 1987 (Box R2)
  - Bermuda Department of Tourism, presentation package, 1999 (Box R3)